Inventory of the Alfred Herrnkind papers, 1935-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Alfred Herrnkind papers
1935-1945
2011C53
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Correspondence and personal documents, relating to German military operations on the Western and Eastern fronts during World War II. Includes some papers of other Herrnkind family members.
Herrnkind, Alfred, 1908-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Sergeant, German army.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence and personal documents, relating to German military operations on the Western and Eastern fronts during World War II. Includes some papers of other Herrnkind family members.
Germany. Heer.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Eastern Front.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Western Front.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.
- Correspondence Received
  - Father, 1940-1945, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1940 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - undated (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - L. Herrnkind, 1940-1944, undated
    - 1940 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - 1941 (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - undated (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - General Family, 1914-1945 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - 1914-1945 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - 1935-1944 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - 1943-1944 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - 1944-1945 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Cousin, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Vera Dietrichkeit, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Karl Dreiling, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Emma Herrnkind, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Gerda Herrnkind, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Fissel Family, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Otto Klingebiel, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Carmen López, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Heinz Martini, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Otto Pasch, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Theo Rose, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Paul Schellhaas, F.W. Wolffram, 1940-1944 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Otto Sier, 1937, 1940 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Simon, 1939, 1943 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - F.W. Wolffram, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - 1936, 1939-1941 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - 1941-1943 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - 1942-1944 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- Correspondence received by L. Herrnkind from Gerda Herrnkind, 1940 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- Personal Documents, 1940-1944
  - Identification, Financial Documents, Notebooks, 1933-1944 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Military Documents, German-French Military Issue Phrasebook, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Résumé, 1942 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Receipts, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 3: 12)